ZiMuZu
倾情奉献
翻译
草草告别狂人们
磁芯升级成机械章鱼X
翻译
电脑团
小酸奶!
翻译
吃冰棒
TL
翻译
时间轴
大葱ALX  念念  今
电脑狂人
第四季
第九集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
我想搜到完美的礼物
世界和平
你想搜什么
彗星
你得看看这个不是我发的哦
网络名录
雅虎
开始了
It's starting.
我在搜什么
What am I looking for?
私制唱片
For bootlegs...
四分之三英尺管钳
3/4-inch socket wrench.
全城最好的咖啡
For the best coffee in the city.
薇诺娜·赖德  我好喜欢她
Winona Ryder. So into her.
园林用品
Landscaping supplies?
-鞋子  -鞋子
- Shoes. - Shoes.
生命的意义  哥们
For the meaning of life, bra.
我想搜些有趣的东西
I'm looking for something funny.
我想搜到灵感
I'm looking for inspiration!
我想搜到治疗方法
I'm looking for a cure.
-我想搜...  -我想搜...
- I'm looking for... - I'm looking for...
我想搜...
I'm looking for...
哥们  互联网
Dude, the Internet.
-互联网  -互联网
- The Internet? - The Internet.
我都在互联网上搜什么
What in God's name would I look for on the Internet?
你可以...
Yeah, you could...
在互联网上找到一切
...find just about anything on the Internet.
好吧  这是一个广告
Okay -- it's, uh, a commercial.
广告是为了卖出产品
And commercials exist to sell products.
但这不仅是件产品  不是的
But this isn't just a product. It isn't.
这是一种新的联接方式
It's a new way of connecting.
新的存在方式
A new way of being.
点开
Hit it.
这是新版彗星  将于今晚发布
So, this is the new Comet, and it launches tonight.
我们不再是人们
No longer are we just a way station
探索路上的中转站了
on people's journey someplace else.
我们就是目的地
We are the destination.
这多亏了在座每一位的努力
This is the combined effort of every single person here,
从最开始的冲浪者
from our original surfers
到卡梅伦·豪伊带领的编码团队
to our coding team headed up by Cameron Howe.
干得好  卡梅
Good job, Cam!
现在已经完成重新上线
It's Cameron's last day
今天也是卡梅伦在这里的最后一天了
now that work on the relaunch is complete...
别这样  我们都知道她总有一天要离开我们
Settle down. We all knew her days were numbered.
我还想提一个人
So, one more person I'd like to mention.
这个地方的一个重要灵魂人物已经不在了
A huge part of the soul of this place is no longer here.
但这是一项家族事业
But this is a family business.
彗星始于海莉·克拉克
Comet began with Haley Clark.
她爸爸和我在1983年结识
Her dad and I met back in 1983.
我告诉他  "电脑不是终点
And I told him, "Computers aren't the thing.
只是我们达到终点的工具"
They're the thing that gets us to the thing."
这就是...
And this is the...
彗星  彗星
Com-IT! Com-IT!
彗星  彗星  彗星
Com-IT! Com-IT! Com-IT!
彗星  彗星
Com-IT! Com-IT!
好啊
All right!
继续吧
Back to it!
-我们可以讨论一下...  -我们有些模型
- Think we can, uh, discuss that -- - We have some mock-ups.
好的  五分钟
Yeah, five minutes.
你没事吧
You okay?
嗯  等下一起庆祝啊
Yeah. Celebrate later?
好  你想怎么庆祝
Yeah. What you wanna do?
就...一起吃晚饭
Just...get some dinner
找个地方停车亲热之类的
and make out in a parked car somewhere?
脱掉衣服  来点点心
A little over-the-clothes stuff and some dim sum.
那我去和大家告别
So I guess I will say goodbye to the guys,
然后打给阿莱克莎了
and, uh, I can call Alexa.
当然了  好的
Of course. Yeah.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
请乘坐国泰航空590航班
at this time, we are now boarding
直达曼谷的乘客
our main-cabin passengers onto Pacific Flight 590,
开始登机
with nonstop service to Bangkok.
我差点忘了  等等
I almost forgot. Hang on.
-这是什么  -这是个旅行记事簿
- What is this? - That is a travel organizer.
我在里面放了一张小型曼谷地图
I put a little map of Bangkok in there.
还能在里面放一些零钱
Compartments for loose change
你的护照和旅行支票
and, um, your passport, traveler's checks.
妈妈  我不要这个
Mom, I'm not taking this.
为什么
Why?
因为我是18岁  不是45岁
Because I'm 18 and not 45.
我要住招待所
I'm staying in hostels.
如果你想让我被抢
If you actually want me to get mugged,
我拿着LV钱包到处逛就行了
I'll walk around with a Louis Vuitton wallet.
妈妈  这是我的旅行
Mom, this is my trip.
我希望你能将我当做一个成年人
I just wish you'd treat me like an adult.
而且我的确是
Which I am, by the way.
你...
You...
好吧
Fine.
注意安全
Be safe.
好
Okay.
-再见  -天啊
- Bye. - Oh, my God.
我的车钥匙在我桌子上
Keys to my Civic are on my desk.
拿我的旧驾照吧
Take my old driver's license, okay?
以防万一
Just in case.
照片是以前拍的  不过
It's an old photo, but...
警察不会怀疑你的  你这么可爱
the cops will believe you 'cause you're a cute girl.
不过保险起见还是戴顶帽子吧
Maybe wear a hat just in case.
好
Yeah.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
这是直飞曼谷的
this is the final boarding call
国泰航空590航班
for the Cathay Pacific Flight 590...
-好吧  -最后一次登机呼叫
- Okay. - ...with nonstop service to Bangkok.
别走
Don't go.
你不用走的
You don't have to go.
我不知道你为什么非得现在走
I don't know why you have to do this right now.
你该  留下来
You should just... just stay.
你别说胡话了  妈
This is such bullshit, Mom.
我们走吧  妈
Let's go, Mom.
医生抱怨他老婆
The doctor complains to his wife
最近夫妻生活不和谐了
that she ain't so good in bed anymore.
他去上班
Well, he goes to work.
到了中午他打电话给她
And by midday, he calls her on the phone.
然后电话响啊响
And the phone rings and it rings...
就是没人接
And it rings and it rings.
然后她终于接了  气喘吁吁的
And, uh, finally, she picks up. She's out of breath.
然后他问  "你怎么这么半天不接电话"
And he goes, "What the hell took you so long to answer the phone?"
然后她说
And she says...
说想再找个人[医生]看看  是吧
Something about a second opinion, right?
是啊  就是这样
Yeah. That's the one.
支架看起来还行
So...stent looks pretty good.
嗯
Yeah.
有没有呼吸困难  胸痛之类的
Any shortness of breath, chest pains?
没有
No. No.
就是有时候解大便太使劲会头晕
Get a little light-headed sometimes if I shit real big.
我还没问过你  莱韦克
You know, I never asked you -- Levecq --
这是哪里的名字
what the hell kinda name is that?
莱韦克  是瑞典名字吗
Levecq? Is it, uh...Swedish?
还是挪威的  还是
Or...is it Norwegian, or...
还是捷克  捷克斯洛伐克那块的
Is it a Czech-- Czechoslovakian?
还是法属加拿大
Little French Canadian there?
荷兰
Dutch.
你没问题了
You're good to go.
好吧  可是
Okay, but -- wh--
我什么时候再回来
When do you want me to come back?
不用回来
I don't.
不用观察复诊什么的吗
Well, not even for a look-see?
你不用确定我情绪稳定什么的吗
I mean...don't you want to make sure I'm not blowing a gasket?
不用
Nope.
觉得不舒服  就打电话
Something goes wrong, call.
没不舒服的话  就不用
If doesn't, don't.
你很健康  约翰
You're in good health, John.
如果你好好保养
If you take care of yourself,
没准能活到21世纪呢
you'll live well into the 21st century.
21世纪
21st century.
真特么...
Son of a...
马克·安德雷森和吉姆·克拉克
So then Marc Andreessen and Jim Clark
飞到厄巴纳-香槟
fly out to Urbana Champaign,
把所有马赛克程序员叫来开餐会
gather all the Mosaic coders in a pizza joint,
给他们六万五的年薪
and offer them $65,000 salaries,
乘他的游艇去大溪地度一周的假
a-a week's vacation on his yacht in Tahiti,
以及公司的十万股股份
and 100,000 shares of the company.
克拉克还告诉他们如果他们离开超算中心
And Clark tells them that if they leave NCSA
转而为他工作
and come work for him,
他们的公司五年之内就会市值破千万
they'll be worth $10 million in less than five years.
所以吉姆·克拉克把一家烂公司的
So Jim Clark steals all the best coders
最好的程序员都偷来去做更好的事
from a shitty company to go do something way better...
怎么听着这么耳熟呢
Why does that sound familiar?
总之我是想说他们都跟他走了
Anyway, my point is that they've all followed him
来到了硅谷  做出了一款浏览器
out to Silicon Valley to build a browser,
而现在网景就要碾压马赛克了
and now Netscape is about to demolish Mosaic.
如果我们要想在网景内置彗星
If we were to launch Comet inside Netscape,
就算能正常载入  也会慢得要死
it'd be slow as hell, if it even loads correctly.
如果不成的话  那流浪者和其他对手也不行
And if it doesn't, then Rover won't or any of our competitors.
但如果我们能想出办法
But if we can figure out a way
让彗星在网景上运行流畅
to make Comet run smoothly on Netscape,
那所有的用户都会流向我们
then all of their users will flock to us.
但那些创造了马赛克的人
But those guys created Mosaic.
他们已经知道怎么制作能正常运行的浏览器
They already know how to make a browser that runs.
但他们不能复制他们自己的成果
But they can't replicate what they've already done.
马赛克已经注册知识产权了
The Mosaic code is intellectual property.
就像BIOS一样
Like the BIOS.
是啊  就像BIOS
Yeah, like the BIOS.
而只有投放市场后  他们才能知道效果如何
And they won't know how it works until it's out in the wild.
而且他们
And -- And...they...
他们会希望使网景比马赛克更强
They'll want to make Netscape better than Mosaic.
乔  你到底想说什么
Joe...what are we doing here?
你完全可以在床上告诉我
You could've told me all of this in bed.
声卡坏了
The sound card's blown.
除了这个  其他都很好
Other than that, it runs perfectly.
好吧
'Kay.
我还需要请你帮个忙
I need one more thing from you.
是个小忙  等网景发售之后
It's a quick job. When Netscape launches,
我们得拆分其代码  让彗星能更快地载入
we pull apart the code so that Comet can load fast.
所以你就拿《飞天蜈蚣》贿赂我
And you're bribing me with Centipede?
如果我们能做成  那我们就有了一件展示品
If we can pull this off, we'll have a -- a showpiece
能让吉姆·克拉克用来强化他的作品
to offer Jim Clark so he can promote his baby.
他们会求我们成为他们架构的一部分
They will beg for us to be a part of their infrastructure.
好吧
Okay.
我们不能等网景上市  那样就太晚了
We can't wait until Netscape launches. It's too late.
我们得优化彗星
We have to optimize Comet
让它第一天就能高速运行
so that it's running fast on Day One.
如果你想给吉姆·克拉克展示
Which, if you want a showcase for Jim Clark...
今天我们就得开始拆分网景的代码
we need to start pulling apart the Netscape code today.
但他们不可能给我们一份调试版拷贝
But there's no way they're going to just give us a working copy.
没错
Oh, no, they won't.
我去打个电话
Let me make a call.
我爱你
I love you.
什么声音
What is that sound?
是戈登的腕表
It's Gordon's wristwatch.
他需要吃药时就会响
It would go off when he needed to take his medication.
我不知道办公室钥匙在哪
I don't know where the key to the office is.
好吧
Okay.
我今天去找个锁匠
I'll call a locksmith today.
你想玩玩吗
Do you want to play?
好啊
Sure.
好
All right.
西雅图如何
How, uh -- How was Seattle?
湿漉漉的
Soggy.
抱歉这样突然出现
Sorry about the ambush.
我看到你的车停在车道上
I saw your car parked in the driveway,
但没有人应门铃
and nobody answered when I rang the bell.
你感觉如何  送琼妮走
How was it? Sending Joanie off?
还好
You know, fine.
只希望她注意安全
Just hope she stays safe.
詹妮弗在斯坦福安顿下来了吗
How's Jennifer settling in at Stanford?
她第一个周末回家了一趟
Well, she was home the first weekend.
洗衣服  偷食吃
Doing laundry, stealing food.
-嗯  -去年这时
- Yeah. - Last year at this time,
我想都不忍去想她离家上大学
I couldn't bear the thought of her leaving for college.
而现在  我倒希望她能再走远点
And now...I kinda wish she'd at least left the zip code.
好吧
Yeah, well...
我们有个好消息
So...we have news.
金柏莉怀孕了
Kimberly is pregnant.
什么  恭喜
Wh-- I-- Congratulations!
太棒了
That's amazing.
对  也不是  但谢谢了
Yeah. No, but thanks.
但趁她还能坐飞机  我们全家想去
But the whole family wants to take a big trip to Ireland
爱尔兰玩一趟
while she can still fly.
约翰和我想自己出去玩玩
And John and I would like to do some traveling of our own --
我明白  你准备迈向新生活了
No, I know. You're ready to move on.
唐娜  我理解  你这段时间不容易
Donna, I understand. It's been hard.
但已经过去四个月了
But it's been four months.
我需要知道你在做什么
And I need to know what you're doing.
我在游泳
I'm swimming.
一切都已经搞定了
We have greased the rails.
执行合伙人是你的了
Managing partner is yours.
没跑了
Period.
你说想和女儿一起过夏天
You said you wanted the summer to be with your girls.
我理解  但是夏天已经过完了  唐娜
I heard that. But the summer is over, Donna.
你等得越久  就越难
The longer you wait, the harder it's gonna get.
崔普和他的手下每天在办公室耀武扬威
Trip and his stooges are strutting through that office every day
觉着自己能比你做得好
thinking they can run it better than you.
他们觉得你怂了
They think you're getting soft.
如果你不想干  没关系
Look, if you don't want this, it's okay.
我们可以谈那个
We can have that conversation.
但你要做个决定
But you need to make a decision.
好吧
Okay, well...
好好想想
give it some thought,
决定了告诉我
and let me know.
你一定是在逗我
You got to be kiddin' me.
不会吧
Whaaat?
你回来得比我想的晚
You're home later than I thought.
旅途如何
How was the trip?
挺好的
It was good.
抱歉  我下飞机回家的路上顺道去看了下唐娜
Sorry, I stopped to see Donna on the way home from the airport.
所以结论如何
Well, so what's the verdict?
我们要展翅高飞去看世界
We gonna sprout wings and see the world
还是她准备在那个游泳池里漂一辈子
or is she gonna float in that swimming pool forever?
我不知道
You know, I don't know.
我去洗下风尘
I'm gonna go wash the plane off me.
好  这些是什么东西
All right. Hey, what is all this stuff?
可能是本的一些旧玩意
Some of Ben's old junk, I suppose.
你一个人的时候都做了些什么
What have you been doing with your bachelorhood?
到处晃
Well, you know, fartin' around.
搞点这个搞点那个  看医生
This and that. Went to the doctor.
他宣布我健康了
Got a clean bill of health.
他说我能健康活到21世纪
He said I should live well into the 21st century.
你能想象吗
You imagine that?
人人都背着飞行器  机器人主宰世界
Jet packs and robot overlords.
看看我还发现了什么
Look what I found, too.
你敢相信吗  这是卡迪夫原版的
Can you believe this? This is a Cardiff original.
我年轻时还亲手把这玩意
I could've packed this thing in a box myself
打包装箱呢  天呐
when I was a teenager. My God.
我敢说还好使呢
I bet it still works.
只需要换块电池
I just need to get some batteries for it.
怎么了
What?
亲爱的  怎么了
Honey, what?
-怎么了  -抱歉  我
- What? - I'm sorry, I...
你会没事了
You're gonna be okay.
是啊  我没事
Yeah, I'm okay
我没事
I'm okay.
我会好好的
I'm gonna be okay.
老天
Mercy.
你真是没夸大你身上的风尘味儿啊
You weren't kidding about that plane goo, were ya?
去吧  好好搓搓洗洗
Come on! Get to scrubbing!
瞧瞧
Look at ya.
我们要怎么为网景优化
But how do we optimize for Netscape
它还不存在呢
if there's no Netscape yet?
我明白  我也在想办法
Look, I get it. And I'm trying to figure it out.
但与此同时  我们还得
But in the meantime, we still have to go through --
好的  稍等
Okay. One second.
给你的
For you.
天  谢谢
Oh, God. Thank you.
不客气
Sure.
来  我带你转转
Here, let me show you out.
这就是彗星
So this is Comet.
是的
Yeah.
我今天看到水星了
I -- I saw the Mercury today.
你做的机器人技术的那个看起来太酷了
God, the robotics thing you're doing looks so cool.
我和他们几周后要飞去参加大会
I'm flying out with those guys in a few weeks --
在巴黎大学  你也该一起来
conference at the Sorbonne. You should come.
这
That's --
我觉得这东西非常有意思
I mean, I find all that stuff super fascinating,
但不是我擅长的
but...it's not really my thing.
-是吧  -不  我懂
- Right? - No, I know.
但就去几天  费用全包
But it's just a couple of days. All expenses paid.
最坏的情况也就是
Worst that happens?
遇见一些很棒的人
You meet some fascinating people
吃了太多热月龙虾
and eat too much lobster thermidor.
是啊
Yeah.
下次吧
Next time.
上次你就这么说
Is what you said last time.
我明白
Look, I know that --
我说了你很多好话  大家都很感兴趣
I've been talking you up. People are really interested.
那很棒
And that's...great.
听着  我知道这段时间很艰难
Hey, look, I'm sure that it's been a tough time
对你们都是
for all of you.
我也明白你想帮朋友一把
And I get that you're trying to help a friend out.
当然  我还年轻  所以懂得不多
And I'm young, so, you know, what do I know.
但是你被责任所累
But you can get so tied up in your obligations
而忘了你最大的责任是对自己的未来
you forget your biggest obligation is to your future self.
我明白
I know that.
好吧
Okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
还有
And...
说真的  这是最后一次了
Seriously, this is the last thing.
但愿如此
I hope so.
但这些是老大的虾
But these are, like, huge shrimps,
就不该叫虾了
like, should not be called shrimp,
上面还有那种小小的触须一样的东西
and had those, like, little feeler touchy things still attached?
不会吧
No!
-真的  -不
- Yes! - No.
超大盘  油炸的
Huge plate, deep-fried,
那些像触须一样的东西有这么长
and those...feeler things were, like, this long.
-拜托  -不
- Come on. - Oh, no.
快告诉我你没吃
Please tell me you didn't eat one.
那是商务晚宴  我必须得吃
It was a business dinner. I had to.
所以我喝了一大口清酒  拿起了一个  然后
So I took a glug of saké, picked one up, and just...
我的天哪
Oh, good lord.
你真是太恶心了
You're disgusting.
这就是我的经历
That's my story.
好了  乔  该你了
Okay, Joe, you're up.
好  鼠海豚睾丸
Yeah. Uhh... Porpoise testicles.
乔...
Joe...
你不可能吃了鼠海豚睾丸
you did not eat porpoise testicles.
我百分之百吃了
I 100% did.
吃鼠海豚的任何部位都是非法的
It is not legal to even eat any porpoise anything.
我吃了那些鱼卵蛋
I ate those fishy balls.
真的吃了
I did.
鼠海豚有睾丸吗
Do porpoises even have testicles?
应该有吧  其实鼠海豚到底是什么
I think so. I mean, what is porpoise?
我觉得那应该是鼠海豚
I mean, yeah. I think it was a porpoise.
管它是什么  那东西很湿软
But whatever it was, it was -- it was squishy,
然后我吐了
and I vomited...
吐到了阴沟里  唐娜  到你了
into the gutter, and... Donna, you're up.
好  生牛肉片
Yeah. All right -- beef carpaccio.
味道超奇怪
So weird.
卡梅伦以前会
Cameron will do this thing
-弄一个...  -什么
- where she can, uh, like, set up, uh... - What?
香肠  蛋黄酱  泡菜的装配流水线
an assembly line of bologna, mayonnaise and pickles.
不  不是泡菜  是酸黄瓜
No, not pickles -- cornichon.
-是  没错  -我说错了
- And, yes, duh... - I'm corrected.
非常美味  你弄一碟蛋黄酱
it's delicious. You get a pile of mayonnaise,
一碟酸黄瓜
pile of cornichon,
把酸黄瓜在蛋黄酱里蘸一下
dip the cornichon in the mayonnaise,
塞到香肠里  扔进嘴里
wrap it in bologna, pop it in your mouth.
听起来好恶心
That's pretty gross.
你们有琼妮的消息吗
So have you guys heard from Joanie?
有
Yeah.
她去了大皇宫
Uh, she went to the Grand Palace,
那儿有一个很大的大象园
and she saw this huge elephant park
还有一个叫真理寺的建筑
and something called the Sanctuary of Truth,
是一座大型的全木质结构寺庙
which is this massive temple carved totally out of wood.
第二晚  她遇到了季风
And on her second night, there was this monsoon?
但和这儿的不一样  那里的雨很暖和
But it's not like here, the rain was super warm,
所以她就去大街上跑  全身都湿透了
so she went running through the streets and she got all soaked
最后去一个小摊吃了碗面
and she ended up eating noodles in this little shack
和一些陌生人交了朋友
and made friends with these total strangers,
他们现在要徒步旅行去普吉岛了
and now they're all backpacking to Phuket.
好棒啊
That's awesome.
我知道  就好像...
Yeah, I know. It's like...
她决定要做什么
She decides she want to do something,
就去做了  你知道吗
and she just does it, you know?
那她接下来要去哪里
Where's she going next?
我不知道
I don't know.
我也不知道
她打来时我没跟她说上话
I, uh, didn't get a chance to talk to her when she called.
她只跟海莉聊了
She just spoke to Haley, so...
海莉  我想给你看样东西
Hey, Haley. There's something I want to show you.
跟我来
Come with me.
嗯  去看看吧
Yeah, go check it out.
-好  -我们收拾
- Okay. - We'll clean up.
是广告
It's the commercial.
我一直想给你看来着
I've just been dying to show it to you.
不  算了吧
Oh...no, that's -- that's okay.
不  你一定得看  来吧
No, you got to see this. Come on.
我们哪天该去吃顿午饭
We got to grab lunch soon.
聊聊最近的事
Catch up, you know?
好啊
Yeah, sure.
抱歉  我们并不是真要洗盘子
Sorry. We're not actually gonna do the dishes.
乔洗盘子有很特定的方式
Um, Joe likes the dishes done in a very paicular way,
而我不会那么洗
and I'm not good at doing them like that,
所以我就干脆不洗了
so I just don't do them anymore.
你现在是新黛安了
Hey, so you're the new Diane now.
不是的  还没正式定下来呢
Oh...Yeah, no. I mean, nothing's official yet.
我还在考虑我究竟想不想要
I'm still trying to decide if I even want it.
什么  你当然想要了
What? Of course you want it.
是啊  只是
Yeah, you know, it's just,
我已经不怎么管创意方面的工作了
I'm already so far removed from the creative side of things.
做了执行合伙人就更糟了  懂吧
And it only gets worse if you're managing partner, you know?
跟阿莱克莎怎么样了
How are things with Alexa?
你在做什么新东西吗
Are you, uh, you working on something new?
算是吧
Kinda. Yeah.
天呐  她刚拿到个...
God, she just scored with this --
是啊  机器人那个
Oh, yeah, the robotics thing.
机器人  是的  水星
Robotics, yeah, yeah, yeah. The Mercury...
嗯  天啊  我真怀念那个
Yeah. Ugh. God, I miss that.
做事情
Doing things.
嗯
Yeah.
她其实也不做什么
I mean, it's not like she actually did anything.
她就是负责找人
She just found those people, you know?
她并不亲手去做的
She doesn't really get her hands dirty.
怎么  你想做点什么吗
Why, do you want to do something?
不是
No.
我也不知道
I don't know.
我就是...
I just --
我好久没自己想出过什么点子了
I haven't had an original idea in kind of a long time.
你想到了社区
Well, you came up with Community.
那就是个
That was just an idea
依附于你的点子的点子
that percolated down from one of your ideas.
并不是那样的
That's not totally accurate.
而且  点子也不是工作本身
And, anyway, ideas are, like, not the work.
是啊
Yeah.
你的工作
I mean, what you do --
并不仅仅是签支票
it's more than just signing a check.
我现在明白了
I-I get that now.
那我不是寄生虫咯
So I'm not parasite?
你不是寄生虫
You're not a parasite.
什么啊
What the hell.
等等  海莉  等等
Hey, hold on. Haley, wait.
是因为
Is it because...
见到他很怪吗
It's weird to see him.
怪吗
Is it weird?
是啊  看到我死去的爸爸
Yeah, it's weird to see my dead dad
出现在一则破广告里很怪
in a stupid commercial.
我出现在里面也很怪  而且你都没问过我
It's weird that I'm in it, and that you didn't even ask me,
我现在都不是那副样子了
and I don't even look like that anymore.
还有怪的是  你把我创造的东西
And it's weird that you've taken this thing that I made,
现在它变成你的了
and -- and now it's yours.
而你只想拿它赚钱
And all you want is to make money off of it!
我明白...
Hey, I understa--
我15了  我不想吃饭
I'm 15! I don't want to have lunch
聊聊近况  什么的
and catch up or whatever.
我不想来参加晚宴
I don't want to be at dinners.
我希望大家都别来烦我
I want everyone to leave me alone.
我去车里了
I'll be in the car.
我会把广告撤下
I'm pulling the ad.
乔
Joe...
你为广告投了很多钱的
Look, you put a lot of money in that commercial.
别就那么打水漂了
Don't just throw it down the drain.
或许你可以把她的部分剪掉
Maybe you can cut her out of it.
这是我的公司
It's my company.
我睡觉前要去干会儿活儿
I'm gonna do some work. Before bed.
什么活儿
What work?
我一直在拖着阿莱克莎那边的事
I've...been putting things off with Alexa.
我得去想想
And, uh...I need to give that some thought.
是我告诉乔可以把你放进广告里的
I gave Joe permission, you know, for you to be in the ad.
如果你生气  也该气我
So if you want to be angry, you should be angry with me.
不怪他的
It's not his fault.
我以为你会喜欢的
I thought you'd like it.
我就是想吃点百吉饼
I just want some Bagel Bites.
海莉  如果你想聊聊
Haley, if there's anything you want to talk about, I'm --
我知道我们说好
Hey, I know we said I'd go back to work
你回学校我就回去工作
as soon as you started back up at school,
但如果你想  我可以留在家
but if you want, I can stay home --
不  我希望你回去工作
No. I want you to go back to work.
我希望你别再那么担心我了
And I want you to stop worrying about me so much.
担心你自己吧
Just, you know, worry about you.
你每天都在家里
You're here all day.
游泳
Swimming.
我喜欢游泳嘛
Well, I like swimming.
嗯  妈妈  我也喜欢游泳  但是拜托
Yeah, Mom, I like swimming, too, but Jesus Christ.
不赖
Not bad.
多好吃
They're incredible.
我回房了
I'm gonna go to my room.
晚安
So good night.
的确很美  是吧
Oh, that is a beaut, huh?
这可可不错
That's good cocoa.
我妈以前会拿真巧克力做
Mama used to make it with real chocolate.
把巧克力放进双层锅炉里化掉
She'd put it in the double boiler and melt it down.
他们卖的那什么破烂速溶的
That instant bullshit they have.
那就是碱化可可粉
It's alkalized cocoa powder, what it is.
是烤完了可可豆
That's the garbage that's left over
剩下的垃圾
after they roast the cocoa beans,
他们经过化学处理
and they run it through a chemical bath
让你尝不出是有多难喝
so you can't taste how awful it is.
天呐  简直是暴殄天物
My God, it's a national travesty.
嗯
Yeah, well...
以前一切都真实多了  是吧
things used to be more real, right?
能看到它们的原理  如何连接在一起
See the way they worked -- this connects to this.
现在都在芯片上了
Now it's just all on a chip.
是啊  就像魔法
Yeah, it's like magic now.
嗯  我不喜欢那种魔法
Ahh, yeah, well... not my kind of magic.
这个怎么那么特别  非得今天修好
What's so special you need to get this thing fixed today, huh?
你是要错过格伦·米勒舞团了吗
You gonna miss the Glenn Miller Orchestra or something?
不  就是心血来潮
No, just got a bug up my butt,
想看看它还能不能用
wanted to see if it still worked.
我以前曾一整天在卡迪夫的工厂里
I used to pack that exact model into boxes all day
把那款机子打包装箱
at the Cardiff factory.
没错
Yeah.
嗯
我还记得那地方的味儿
I can still smell that place.
挺怪的吧
It's weird, isn't it,
你能记住好多早些年的事
how much stuff you remember from early in life?
而中间的部分则...
And how all that stuff in the middle just kinda...
都混在一起了
just kinda runs together.
我已经比我父亲过世时大七岁了
I am seven years older than my father was when he died.
在那之前  他一整天
He spent the whole day before
都在大吼着马龙家的大树的根
yelling about how the tree from the Malone place
会长进下水道里
was gonna bore into that sewer line
害他赔一大笔钱
and cost him a damn fortune.
然后  突然  就倒下了
And then boom, down.
他人生最后一天就在抱怨树根
Just...spent his last day bitching about tree roots.
老爸啊
Oh, Dad.
总之  我就是觉得  如果你想要什么
Anyway, it just seems to me if you want something,
最好去搞定它
best to go get it done.
马上
Now.
现在是投手的对决
It's a real pitchers' duel here.
这才叫魔法
Now, that's magic.
是吧
See?
太完美了
Perfect.
你能...
Hey, would you, uh...
你能让黛安给我打个电话吗
Would you have Diane give me a call?
当然
Will do.
不管了
Ahh, screw it.
告诉她我准备好了
Just tell her I'm ready.
好
Okay.
我在想
So, I was thinking.
我有我姐姐的车
I have my sister's car.
记得我说她要去泰国吗
Because remember how I said she's going to Thailand?
她说那里很棒
Which she says is hella badass.
我知道你肯定也有车
And, I mean, I'm sure you have a car, too,
而且我还不能开车呢
and I'm not even supposed to be driving it yet,
但是  不管了
but...whatever.
我在想
So, um, I was -- I was wondering, um,
你听说过《天生杀人狂》吗
have you h-- have you heard of "Natural Born Killers"?
是的
Yes.
嗯  朱丽叶特·刘易斯真是太赞了
Yeah. Juliette Lewis is awesome,
24世纪在上映
and it's playing at the Century 24,
不过电影那么火  可能都售罄了
but it's super popular so it might be sold out...
-那...  -但如果真没票了
- Oh, well, that's -- - But if it is, uh,
我们还可以去温彻斯特神秘屋
then we could go to the Winchester Mystery House
就在旁边
which is right next door,
他们有午夜游
and they do these midnight tours.
特别酷
Which are dope, I think...
嗯
And, um, yeah.
总之
Anyway, um
我能带你去看《天生杀人狂》吗
could I take you to see "Natural Born Killers"?
等等
Okay, hold on.
马上好了
Hold -- almost.
好了
All right.
行了
Okay.
真是太棒了
It's truly a masterpiece.
是啊
Yeah.
这就是你的西斯廷教堂
This is your Sistine Chapel.
哎呦  我还在那里找到一盒1982年的肥料
Awww, hell. I found a box of Miracle-Gro down there from 1982.
好了
All right.
我不再折腾了
I'm done.
真的
Done, I say.
咱俩来好好生活吧
How about you and I do some actual living?
不能取巧吗
Can't we cheat it?
把彗星重复出现的图像存入
Make it so we that we store recurrent Comet images
用户的网景浏览器缓存中
in the user's Netscape cache?
那样加载就快多了
It would make it load so much faster.
是啊  如果网景支持这功能的话
Yeah, I would, if Netscape supported that,
但并不  所以
but they don't, so...
询问框修好了吗
Is the query box fixed?
还是如果回车前
Or does it still get a null response
多打了空格依然是无响应
if you put a space before the carriage return?
我还在修
Still on my punch list.
乔  这仍是早期测试版本
Joe, this is still an early beta.
有一堆漏洞
So there's tons of bugs.
我们也不知道他们要修什么
We don't know what they're gonna fix,
怎么修  补丁会如何影响我们
how they're gonna fix it, how those fixes are gonna affect us.
那我还是闭嘴吧
Guess I should just shut up.
不是  你能不能放松
No, but could you just relax?
我们有的是时间呢
We've got tons of time.
我们只有两天了
We've got two days.
是的  还有两天呢
Yeah, we have two days.
好吧  看
Okay, here.
那看上去比之前还糟了
That looks worse than it did before.
我知道  这是个过程
I know. It's part of the...process.
或许你不该看香肠是怎么做的
Maybe you shouldn't watch how the sausage is made.
你是在看电邮吗
Are you checking your e-mail?
怎么了
What?
没事
Nothing.
不  怎么了
No, what?
你觉得我态度不够认真吗
What, am I not taking this seriously enough for you?
我没那么说
I didn't say that.
你不用说出来  你就这意思
You didn't have to say it. You're acting like it.
我们有考试的小抄了
We've got the cheat sheet to the exam.
我们赢了
We've won.
我就是不想再错过一个机会
I just don't want to miss another opportunity.
两天
Two days.
两天  我没别的要求
Two days. That's all I'm asking for.
你能不能集中注意足够长的时间
Can you just focus long enough
让我们把彗星优化好
for us to get Comet optimized...
-天呐  -等网景发布后  能做到完美加载
- Oh, my God. - ...so that it loads perfectly when Netscape ships.
我很专注了
I'm giving you my focus.
天呐  我是在帮你个忙
Jesus, I'm doing you a favor.
电邮是谁发的
Who's the e-mail from?
阿莱克莎
Alexa.
那去吧
Go ahead.
读吧
Read it.
天
Oh, g--
是新测试版
It's the new beta.
我要替你感谢她吗  还是你想自己编点
Shall I thank her for you, or do you want to compose something
会让她为帮你忙而觉得自己蠢的话
that'll make her feel like a total shitbag for helping you out?
饶了我吧
Give me a break.
好了
Okay.
看上去跟之前的一样
Looks the same as the old one.
是啊  外表是一样的  看看运行起来如何吧
Yeah, the skin's the same. Let's see how she runs.
这可比我想的快多了
That's way faster than I thought.
是啊
Yeah.
等等
Hold on.
页面还没完全加载出来你就能输入文字了吗
What, you can put text in fields before the page fully loads?
真是厉害
Really nice touch.
好的  他们支持JPEG图片
Okay, so they've got support for JPEG.
排版太棒了
The formatting is perfect.
我要给吉姆·克拉克打个电话
I'm gonna set a call with Jim Clark.
知道我们可以做什么吗
You know what we could do?
我们可以在主页上放个标签
We could put a badge on our homepage
"已为网景优化"
saying "Optimized for Netscape."
那样gif动图就能流畅...
And the gifs would render smoothly if --
等等
Wait, wait...
那是什么  之前没有的
What is that? That wasn't there before.
雅虎是什么
What the hell is Yahoo?
斯坦福大学俩人做的  以前叫做
Two guys. Stanford. Used to be called
"杰瑞和大卫的互联网向导"
"Jerry and David's Guide to the World Wide Web."
但是
But...
这好烂  设计得太差了
This sucks. The design's terrible,
也没有图像  而且
there's no image support, they're --
在工具栏上
On the toolbar.
什么
What?
他们在工具栏上
They're on the toolbar.
完了
That's it.
他们赢了
They've won.
他们是网络的名录了
They're the directory to the Web.
我们不存在
We don't exist.
天呐
Oh, God.
拜托
Come on.
乔
Joe.
Joe!
有咖啡
There's coffee.
我不用了
I'm all right.
我希望它成功的
I wanted it to work.
我希望我们成功
I wanted us to work.
是吗
Yeah?
我也是
Me too.
它成功了
It did.
成功了一阵
For a while.
是啊
Yeah.
是达到终点的工具
The thing that gets you to the thing.
是你
It was you.
一直都是你
It was always you.
谢谢  谢谢大家
Thank you. Thank you all.
我们开始吧
Let's, uh, get right down to it, shall we?
很高兴你改主意了
Glad you reconsidered.
我就是为热月龙虾来的
I'm just going for the lobster thermidor.
再回到网络搜索上来
...and to circle back to Web search,
我得知网景本周发行时
I got word that when Netscape launches this week,
雅虎将成为默认名录
Yahoo will be the default directory.
他们还有自己的按钮什么的
They've got their own button and everything.
彗星要完了
So Comet is pretty much kaput.
而且
And --
那么流浪者呢
Uh-- so, where does that leave Rover?
应该拆分出售  在企业对企业市场上卖掉
Should off-load it for parts, sell it on the B2B market.
幸好  它是基于算法
Lucky for us, it's algorithm-based,
所以还有些价值
so it actually has some value.
有个...什么来着  班基
There's a -- What is it, Benji? It's a...
医疗索引公司
medical indexing company
表现出了兴趣
that's actually expressed some interest, so...
我们该看看那个
We should probably look into that one
努力争取卖到20%到30%的价值
and try to get 20% to 30% of value and --
倒回去
Hey, go back.
那个网景的搜索名录叫什么
What is Netscape's search directory called?
是...雅虎
It's, uh...Yahoo?
抱歉  是什么
I'm sorry, what is it?
"雅虎"
It's "Yahoo"?
雅虎
Ya-hoo?
对  雅虎  就是"呀呼"还有个...
Yeah, Yahoo. Like, "Yahoo," with a...
惊叹号
with an exclamation point.
雅虎  还有个惊叹号  不是问号
Oh, Yahoo with an exclamation point, not a question mark?
因为你总是说得像"雅虎?"
'Cause you keep saying Yahoo with a question mark,
-我就...  -好吧
- so I was... -Okay.
应该是  雅虎!吧
Shouldn't it be more like...Yahoo!
好吧
Sure.
拜托
Come on.
跟我一起深入进去  崔普
Drill down with me now, Trip.
雅虎
Yahoo!
Yahoo.
不对啊
No, man! No!
天呐
Oh, Jesus!
使点劲啊
Now put some mustard on it, you know?!
雅虎
Yahoo!
不对  雅虎
No, no, no! Ya-hooooooooo!
雅虎
Ya-hooooooooo!